YANAN WU

+1 (607) 372-0368 | yxw190021@utdallas.edu

gisynw.com | linkedin.com/in/giswu | github.com/gisynw | ywu120766.medium.com/

SUMMARY

PhD Student in the Geospatial Information Sciences Department at the University of Texas at Dallas. 2 years of teaching experience as an instructor, guiding students to achieve success in learning geographic information science (GIS) and statistics. Excellent written and verbal communication skills evident by extensive conferences and awards. Proven problem-solving, relationship-building, and negotiation through academic and research experience as a Teaching Assistant and a Research Assistant.

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosophy in Geospatial Information Sciences

The University of Texas at Dallas

Master of Arts in Geography

Binghamton University

Bachelor of Science in Resource Environment and Urban-Rural Planning Management

May 2016

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

• Teaching Assistant 2022 – Current

EPPS 2302 Methods of Quantitative Analysis in the Social and Policy Science

• Instructor 2021 – 2022

GISC 3304 Principles of Geospatial Information Sciences

Xi'an University of Science and Technology, China

EPPS 2302 Methods of Quantitative Analysis in the Social and Policy Science

• Teaching Assistant 2020-2021

GISC 6325 Remote Sensing Fundamentals

GISC 4325 Introduction to Remote Sensing

GISC 4386 Global Changes and its Challenges

GISC 3304 Principles of Geospatial Information Science

• Research Assistant 2019 – 2020

Participated in the NIST-funded research project: SAFE-NET An Integrated Connected Vehicle and Computing Platform for Public Safety Applications

• Graduate Assistant 2017 – 2019

Produce global remote sensing image; detect changing pattern of lakes from GRACE data

PUBLICATIONS

Wu, Y., Yang, Y., & Yuan, M. (2023). Location analytics of routine occurrences (LARO) to identify locations with regularly occurring events with a case study on traffic accidents. *Information* (Under review)

Wu, Y., Yang, Y., & Yuan, M. (2023). Understanding the role of geographical environments in emergency dispatches with GPS trajectories. *Abstracts of the ICA*, 6, 276.

Wu, Y., & Yuan, M. (2021). Where and why there: location analytics of routine occurrences (LARO) with a case study on traffic accidents. *Abstracts of the ICA*, 3, 318.

CONFERENCE PROCEEDINGS

Wu, Y., Yang, Y., Yuan, M. Analyze emergency-vehicle dispatches in Dallas, Texas, USA, In AutoCarto 2022 Proceedings.

Yang, Y., Wu, Y., Yuan, M. Quantifying the impacts of social infrastructure on human networks, In AutoCarto 2022 Proceedings.

AWARDS

- 2023 Second Place in Graduate Paper Competition, SWAAG conference
- 2023 International Cartographic Association Scholarship
- 2023 Travel award from USNC for ICA with NSF funding to attend the ICC2023
- 2023 Betty & Gifford Johnson Travel Award, UTD

2022	Graduate student participants of the Grad WINGS Workshop, UCGIS
2022	International Cartographic Association Scholarship
2022	Second Place, Student Lightning Talk Award, UCGIS Symposium
2022	Third Place in GIS Day 2022 Awarded by Geospatial Information Sciences Program, UTD
2022	Travel award from UCGIS to attend the UCGIS Symposium
2022	The University of Texas at Dallas 2022 Three Minute Thesis (3MT) Competition, Finalist
2022	Honorable mentions, GI Science & Systems Student Honors Paper Competition session, AAG
2021	International Cartographic Association Scholarship
2021	Travel award from USNC for ICA with NSF funding to attend the ICC2021
2021	Pioneers Student Research Fund, Geospatial Information Sciences Program, UTD
2021	PhD Research Small Grants Awarded by the Office of Graduate Education, UTD
2021	First Place in GIS Day 2021 Awarded by Geospatial Information Sciences Program, UTD
2019	First Place in GIS Day 2019 Awarded by Geospatial Information Sciences Program, UTD
2019	Pioneers Student Research Fund, Geospatial Information Sciences Program, UTD
2019	First Place in GIS Day 2019 Awarded by the Geography Department at Binghamton University
2015	Outstanding Prize in GeoDesign at Esri GIS Software Development Contest
PRESE	NTATIONS
2023	Identify geographical environments influencing emergency response performance. SWAAG,
2023	Modeling of emergency incident with GPS trajectory data using random forest algorithm. ICC, August
2023	Assessing the role of geographical context in modeling the likelihood of emergency response. AAG, April
2022	Driving pattern analysis for emergency vehicle (EV). AutoCarto, November
2022	Understanding emergency vehicle movement from GPS trajectory data. GIS Day in UTD, November
2022	Understanding 911 Response Time from GPS trajectory data. UTD Research Day, October
2022	Driving pattern analysis for emergency vehicle (EV) using multi-source data. UCGIS, Syracuse, NY, June
2022	Why is there a delay in a 911 vehicle arriving? The Three Minute Thesis (3MT) Competition, UTD, April
2022	Location analytics of routine occurrences (LARO) to identify locations with regularly occurring events. CO, April
2022	Location Analytics of Routine Occurrences (LARO) with a case study on traffic accidents. AAG, New York, February
2021	location analytics of routine occurrences (LARO) with a case study on traffic accidents. ICC, Italy, December
2021	Emergency vehicle data map-matching utilizing the Dijkstra's Algorithm. GIS Day in UTD, November
2021	Spatial-temporal analysis of traffic accidents for increasing sustainable transportation. The Center for Spatial Studies at UCSB
2021	The Three Minute Thesis (3MT) Competition. The University of Texas at Dallas, April
2020	Research Showcase Poster Competition, EPPS. The University of Texas at Dallas, October
2019	Visualizing (Wild) Fires in Sentinel-2 imagery using custom script in EO Browser. GIS Day in UTD, November
2019	Developing an hourly risk model for street networks in Dallas. SWAAG, Fort Worth, Texas. October
2019	Integration of Earth observations and in situ data for analyzing lake level changes. GIS Day at Binghamton University, March
2019	Integration of Earth observations and in situ data for analyzing lake level changes. AAG, Washington D.C. April
ACAD	EMIC SERVICE
2022	Student judge for Faculty Three Minutes Thesis (3MT) Competition in UTD

2022 USGIF Student Assistant Program at the 2022 GEOINT Symposium

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS

American Association of Geographers

Cartography and Geographic Information Society